<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Moxels on Skippy&#39;s Symposium</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/moxels/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Moxels on Skippy&#39;s Symposium</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Sebastien Boehme</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:56:46 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/moxels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Argo, or: I don&#39;t know how to organize a story properly</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-argo-or-i-dont-know-how-to-organize-a-story-properly/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:56:46 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-argo-or-i-dont-know-how-to-organize-a-story-properly/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-argo&#34;&gt;The Argo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; So I had this idea, late at night, as all good ideas arrive. An idea for a story based in hard science fiction with mild horror and thriller elements. It&amp;rsquo;s not a terribly sophisticated idea, but I liked the setting and speculative technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-setting&#34;&gt;The Setting
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; I wanted to set this story on an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/O%27Neill_cylinder&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;O&amp;rsquo;Neil cylinder&lt;/a&gt; called the Argo. This has a few advantages, as it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty self-contained environment and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of creative freedom in the environment. However, it&amp;rsquo;s also a helluva a challenge. You have to describe the setting in a way that makes sense to an audience that&amp;rsquo;s spent their entire life on Earth. A quick rundown of features that are hard to describe and unintuitive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The horizon curves up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone on the cylinder can look up and see anywhere else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;inner space&amp;rdquo; between the habitable interior surface and the exposed outer surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gravity &lt;em&gt;decreases&lt;/em&gt; as you go up towards the central spoke.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The wider world of the story is effectively set in the late 2300s, as humanity has started colonizing nearby star systems. FTL is impossible and near-lightspeed travel comes with insurmountable engineering challenges in the form of energy requirements and micrometor impact damage. So, the colonization ships need to be habitats capable of self-sustaining for hundreds, possibly thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This makes for a crazy cool and unique setting, but it&amp;rsquo;s also basically impossible to describe without being a god of prose or using an illustration. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to draw a world that&amp;rsquo;s just so weird and unintuitive, and I&amp;rsquo;m not good at drawing. But, I LOVE this setting, and want to do a lot more with it, but right now, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the illustrative chops to deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-characters&#34;&gt;The Characters
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dae. Our protagonist, a mechanical engineer ~20 years old working on a capstone project. That&amp;rsquo;s literally all that I developed him with. Yeah, he&amp;rsquo;s paper-thin. Following a five-man band structure, he&amp;rsquo;s nominally the Leader, but usually comes off more as the Lancer or Big Buy. When I left the story, he hadn&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marc. Affable ace, best friends with Dae, who&amp;rsquo;s kinda a replacement for his often-absent parents. He switches between the Heart and the Leader. In my mind, I had him the most developed, but it&amp;rsquo;s still not great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ava. Computer programmer on the same capstone project team as Dae. I didn&amp;rsquo;t develop her much personally, but she fulfils the Smart Guy role, sometimes switching in for the Heart. Best friends with Sarah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah. Nominally the leader until she gets damseled and puppeted by Blue Sky. She has very little characterization beyond &amp;ldquo;tough guy who doesn&amp;rsquo;t take shit.&amp;rdquo; She&amp;rsquo;s basically a walking plot device, and while I planned to characterize her with a recovery from being damseled and puppeted, but stopped writing before that. I was going to do a &amp;ldquo;break the badass,&amp;rdquo; but stopped first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antonin. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t even deserve a mention, as he does basically nothing and I practically forget he exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue Sky. A moxel construction designed to maintain the Argo and protect its inhabitants, but has interpreted that directive more broadly than originally intended. It enforces a lower tech level, fights off Red Sky, and puppeteers Sarah. It&amp;rsquo;s basically amoral, only trying to fulfill the objective. Not exactly a protagonist, but was intended to be a protagonist-aligned character after they free Sarah and fight through Blue Sky&amp;rsquo;s swarms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Sky. Calls itself by a numerical address, became a paperclip maximizer focused on terraforming, as it was a bot working on the Martian terraforming effort. Intent on destroying the enclave in the Argo and using the ship&amp;rsquo;s resources to expand to the stars. The antagonist, it&amp;rsquo;s amoral, just as Blue Sky; it just has a very different objective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problems&#34;&gt;the Problems
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m just going to give a list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper-thin characters. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think them through at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uncertain story. I didn&amp;rsquo;t go in with any coherent story in mind besides a few key scenes and some twine between them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Undeveloped world. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; my world worked before writing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Undeveloped character interactions. Besides the relation between Marc and Dae, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have anything in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-fixes&#34;&gt;The Fixes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Writing a proper long-form story is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. I keep underestimating the difficulty and assuming I can plow through with gumption and goodwill. That&amp;rsquo;s not how the world works, and my poor decisions usually catch up with me around page 50. What I need to do is learn to think through a world &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;first&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Make notes, write everything down, come up with an organization system (maybe this website). Whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to organize before, I usually run into issues with quick referencing back - I can&amp;rsquo;t find the information I need. That sounds like an issue with my organization system, and I should probably try to break things down and solve the problem like an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Also, I should write short stories of the different scenes I like to get a feel for the world. The first section of the Argo story isn&amp;rsquo;t actually that bad; I basically wrote it as a short story featuring the characters I&amp;rsquo;d figured out. I think it does an alright job at characterizing them, introducing conflict, and building suspense. Those short stories are also a smaller load to try to think through. They don&amp;rsquo;t require nearly as much long-term planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The main problem I&amp;rsquo;ll run into with trying to write short stories is that I like to think &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt;. My mind will start with a short story and spiral out to the whole fictional world. This spiraling, while enticing and initially fun, tends to gloss over details and introduce inconsistencies. I need to set a specific, pre-defined endpoint to a short story and &lt;em&gt;stick to it&lt;/em&gt;. Anything more can be the subject of a future short story or part of the larger world. Who knows, maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll make its way to a post here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
