<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Skippy&#39;s Symposium</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Skippy&#39;s Symposium</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Sebastien Boehme</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 12:42:43 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Ender 3 Saga</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-ender-3-saga/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 12:42:43 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-ender-3-saga/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-the-ender-3&#34;&gt;So, the Ender 3
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;re as much of a 3D printing nerd as me, you&amp;rsquo;ll know the name. The Ender 3. Some say it with fear or disgust, some with respect. I&amp;rsquo;m somewhere in the middle. Should &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; get an ender 3? Hell no. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend almost anything else - an SVO6 or SVO7 is far better for not much more money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; But there&amp;rsquo;s a reason this printer is so infamous. It&amp;rsquo;s the most popular 3D printer by far, and its successors continue to be quite popular. It has a dedicated modding community, and a heavily modded ender 3 &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y199h1UaJ7U&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;currently holds the world record for fastest speedbenchy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The unfortunate reason this printer is so heavily modded is that it&amp;rsquo;s shit. Creality is not known for their quality control, and that started with the ender 3. Out of the box, mine came with a bent lead screw and bed more warped than a taco. It uses manual leveling with screws and knobs. The tiny 4010 fan is practically an afterthought. &lt;strong&gt;BUT&lt;/strong&gt;, the printer was able to provide a few servicable prints before falling apart. It hooked people by showing them the possibilities of printing before showing them the dark sides of maintenance and calibration. This page is meant to serve as a cautionary tale against the ender 3, but also show what the printer was good at - teaching you, in exquisite and painful detail, &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; how a 3D printer works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-early-years&#34;&gt;The Early Years
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much of this time or how I modded the printer since it was few years ago. All I remember was picking up the printer, naming it Monica, and setting it up one excited evening. The next day was spent leveling, trying out filament, and getting my first real print - a bracket to hold the printer&amp;rsquo;s tools. I still remember the feeling, looking at a part that the printer had created seemingly from thin air. Then, an obligatory benchy for testing, and I was off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; My first large print showed me the flaws of the printer. I had first bought the printer to make anthropological models, as I am a huge fan of human evolution and wanted models of the hominins. I was never able to get really &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; large prints from the ender 3, and that was apparent pretty early on. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember many details, I just remember things not going great, and a few times I considered quitting printing all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I also ended up installing Octoprint at this time, which I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend if klipper isn&amp;rsquo;t your jam. It&amp;rsquo;s stupid simple and only takes a Raspberry Pi. It probably saved a few SD cards and got me used to SSH and Putty, which besides just being a useful skill, is necessary for a klipper install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-road-to-klipper&#34;&gt;The Road to Klipper
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; First, my mainboard broke. It was probably my fault, but I can&amp;rsquo;t really remember. I ended up using the BTT SKR mini v3 as my replacement, and since I&amp;rsquo;d heard of klipper as the &amp;ldquo;better firmware,&amp;rdquo; I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try it out. The ender 3 was the first place I really tried out klipper, and while I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it was an actual benefit over the Octoprint I&amp;rsquo;d been using, it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a nice testbed where I could learn about KIAUH and all the other intricacies and eccentricities of klipper. I never got input shaping on the printer, but I also never really wanted it - it&amp;rsquo;s not as if I&amp;rsquo;m moving fast enough that I need it. This also got me used to the workflows and software I&amp;rsquo;d need for klipperizing future printers, as I&amp;rsquo;ve done for the FLSUN SR. If you like speed and modability, klipper is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;volcano-nozzle&#34;&gt;Volcano Nozzle
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; This, in hindsight, was a terrible idea. I&amp;rsquo;d seen in a CNC Kitchen video that you could use a volcano nozzle right in a standard V6. This is possible, and it works just as he describes in the video - the problem is, it messes up cooling and z offsets. Also, volcano nozzles only improve volumetric flow, an issue I was not having. I (mistakenly) installed a volcano nozzle on a printer that could not benefit from a volcano and only recently learned my lesson. Don&amp;rsquo;t do this unless your cooling and homing setups are ready for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cr-touch&#34;&gt;CR-Touch
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; This was a flat waste of money. The probe broke after about a month. It was a pain to calibrate. That&amp;rsquo;s all I&amp;rsquo;ll really say on the subject. Refer to some lower sections for what you should get instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;klackender&#34;&gt;Klackender
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kevinakasam.com/klackender/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;klackender&lt;/a&gt; is a mostly-free automatic bed probe for the ender 3 that uses common microswitches and magnets to give your printer capabilities similar to the klicky probe found on many Vorons, Ratrigs, and other DIY printers. It&amp;rsquo;s accurate and cheap, but entirely DIY. Luckily, the macros required were provided by KevinAkaSam, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about the headache that can be klipper macros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; BUT, and this is a huge BUT, it&amp;rsquo;s an entirely DIY mod. There are easier ways to do this that aren&amp;rsquo;t too expensive. An inductive probe like a PINDA is $5-15 on aliexpress and a pretty easy mod. Honestly, I&amp;rsquo;d probably recommend the inductive probe over the klackender for most use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hero-me&#34;&gt;Hero Me
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is probably the first upgrade I&amp;rsquo;ll completely remove from my printer. I found that the Hero Me system was bulky and didn&amp;rsquo;t work all that well together. While configurable, it was configurable at the expense of anything else. The system is near-impossible to actually perform maintenance on. I also found that the direct drive mod for the Hero Me didn&amp;rsquo;t work well. Soooo&amp;hellip; yeah. Might work for others, but I had a universally bad experience with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Moxels</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/moxels/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 12:02:22 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/moxels/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-exactly-are-moxels&#34;&gt;So, what exactly are moxels?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; Well, moxels are a fictional technology I like to include in my stories. The phrase is a concatonation of &amp;ldquo;Matter Pixel,&amp;rdquo; as that&amp;rsquo;s basically what a Moxel is: an extension of pixels into 3D matter. Rather than having a computer project images on a screen with lots of tiny pixels, the concept of moxels would allow computers to project 3D objects with lots of tiny moxels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-how-exactly-is-this-supposed-to-work&#34;&gt;And how exactly is this supposed to work?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nanomachines, son&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Or, more seriously, moxels are basically my name for my brand of nanites. The thought is that sometime in the near future, the same technology used to create AMD&amp;rsquo;s 3D CPU chips can be expanded to make small interlocking machines. They&amp;rsquo;re hard to make, as they require exquisite precision only available to the best chip manufacturers and global powers. However, when coupled with the right software, they can be &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; powerful, which brings us to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moxel-applications&#34;&gt;Moxel applications
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; Since these are a fairly maleable plot device, I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a ton of different potential uses moxels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brain-scanning&#34;&gt;Brain scanning
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Having loads of microscopic machines able to form a sensor network allows for very detailed modeling of the human brain. Good enough, in fact, that in some stories, you can upload people by creating a digital copy of their neurons and all their individual links. Unfortunately, that virtual mind takes a lot of processing power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;intelligence-modeling&#34;&gt;Intelligence modeling
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Current neural networks work, in an oversimplified way, with huge nets of nodes connected with weighted values, some nodes simply acting as input and output nodes. This is modeled after meatware brains, where neurons (&amp;ldquo;nodes&amp;rdquo;) are connected to each other with synapses (&amp;ldquo;weighted connections&amp;rdquo;) with sensory neurons (&amp;ldquo;input nodes&amp;rdquo;) and motor neurons (&amp;ldquo;output nodes&amp;rdquo;) on the periphery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Since we model neural networks on brains, what if you had individual small computers acting as neurons in some sort of hybrid? Instead of interacting cells, you&amp;rsquo;d have loads of small machines that perform the same functions as cells. If each machine were to have the same connections and weights as a real neuron, and they were all connected in the same ways as a human brain, could you create a human mind? And if those weights and connections were based on a real person, could you effectively upload that person to a network of small machines instead of a network of small cells?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; In some of my stories, I use this to explain how you could create a person with extraordinary powers while giving those powers limits. In other stories, I use this premise to explain how we create true AI. This is my main way to create antagonists, or occasionally, powerful protagonists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moxel-clouds&#34;&gt;Moxel clouds
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is something I&amp;rsquo;m not including in some of my more recent stories because it can be stupidly powerful. If a moxel can move independently of a body and network with other moxels, well, what stops a moxel-based being from extending a cloud of moxels from themselves to sense the world around themselves? And moreover, what if the moxels in that cloud could be collected and used?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; In stories, this practically amounts to absurdly powerful telekinesis and sensing abilities. This can become an issue physics-wise, as the moxels need to push against air to move through the air. For a microscopic particle, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to handwave the wind created by the movement of moxels, but if you&amp;rsquo;re using the moxel cloud to move things, you need to push on a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of air. No matter how you count it, if you&amp;rsquo;re going to lift a helicopter-sized mass, you need to push a helicopter downdraft-sized mass of air. That is something that characters should notice and need to plan around, but in all my stories with moxel clouds, I&amp;rsquo;ve just handwaved it away and ignored the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s also the issue of power generation and transmission. There&amp;rsquo;s a few ways to handwave this issue, but none that are terribly convincing to me. They&amp;rsquo;re not the worst handwaves I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, and it&amp;rsquo;s not as if you can&amp;rsquo;t handwave for plot purposes, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like them and want to avoid them in the future. You &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; address the power requirements in a few ways. First option is to simply say that each moxel can store a small amount of power in a capacitor and they&amp;rsquo;re quickly refreshing through the cloud, zipping between recharging and the cloud. This would severely limit the size and strength of the moxel cloud, which might actually be very useful is a story. The second option is to use wireless charging, but that requires such huge electrical discharge and is so inefficient I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever use it in a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;teleportation&#34;&gt;Teleportation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This one&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a stretch, and I usually handwave it, but I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the idea of a being that can teleport short distances. In some moxel beings, this makes them hard to hit - they dodge Neo-style. In some, they close the distance between themselves and an enemy almost instantly. In some others, this just means that they phase around and are generally menacing. In the nicer characters, this is just something that means their body looks hazy and their silhouette blurs when they get excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-replication&#34;&gt;Self-Replication
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever really explored this. Granted, if I ever were to, it&amp;rsquo;d be in a very limited sense - not grey goo, but more that moxel-based intelligences can operate and create machinery that creates more moxels. In some other stories, this might be that moxels can absorb mass and convert mass to other moxels, but there are other limits, like the total mass of a moxel being. This is usually just as a way to explain how the characters are able to replenish lost mass and conjure things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moxel-body-types&#34;&gt;Moxel body types
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; This depends a lot on the type of story I&amp;rsquo;m writing and what sort of protagonists and antagonists I want. If the protagonists need to be super powerful, then they&amp;rsquo;ll likely be moxel-based constucts, and I&amp;rsquo;ll portray them as a human (Sometimes a self-insert. Hey, I can indulge a bit.). I explain this as the characters being human uploads, so the array of sensory and motor neurons we have only make sense when mapped to a humanoid body. After all, if you&amp;rsquo;re uploaded to computer, you&amp;rsquo;d probably prefer a humanoid body over anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; But it&amp;rsquo;s not as if there&amp;rsquo;s no perks to being uploaded to moxels. For one, the ability to framejack (a term stolen from Bobiverse) - you can freeze and fast-forward your perception of reality. You can modify your body or create anything from the moxels in your own body. You can basically live in creative mode. Some characters use this for good, some not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The other main body type I portray is the &lt;strong&gt;CUBE&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a simple antagonist, as it&amp;rsquo;s a profoundly non-human entity that probably wants to murder you with a wide variety of unknown capabilities. The cubes aren&amp;rsquo;t all powerful, though. Larger cubes, while more powerful, think far slower, as they have far more nodes that are farther apart, so lightspeed delay between nodes physically slows down their processing. The advantage of size is intelligence - while they make decisions slower, the extra complexity in their neural network means that they make better decisions. On the other end, smaller cubes make worse decisions and aren&amp;rsquo;t as capable, but they&amp;rsquo;re able to react faster and move faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Argo, or: I don&#39;t know how to organize a story properly</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-argo-or-i-dont-know-how-to-organize-a-story-properly/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:56:46 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-argo-or-i-dont-know-how-to-organize-a-story-properly/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-argo&#34;&gt;The Argo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; So I had this idea, late at night, as all good ideas arrive. An idea for a story based in hard science fiction with mild horror and thriller elements. It&amp;rsquo;s not a terribly sophisticated idea, but I liked the setting and speculative technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-setting&#34;&gt;The Setting
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; I wanted to set this story on an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/O%27Neill_cylinder&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;O&amp;rsquo;Neil cylinder&lt;/a&gt; called the Argo. This has a few advantages, as it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty self-contained environment and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of creative freedom in the environment. However, it&amp;rsquo;s also a helluva a challenge. You have to describe the setting in a way that makes sense to an audience that&amp;rsquo;s spent their entire life on Earth. A quick rundown of features that are hard to describe and unintuitive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The horizon curves up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyone on the cylinder can look up and see anywhere else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;inner space&amp;rdquo; between the habitable interior surface and the exposed outer surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gravity &lt;em&gt;decreases&lt;/em&gt; as you go up towards the central spoke.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The wider world of the story is effectively set in the late 2300s, as humanity has started colonizing nearby star systems. FTL is impossible and near-lightspeed travel comes with insurmountable engineering challenges in the form of energy requirements and micrometor impact damage. So, the colonization ships need to be habitats capable of self-sustaining for hundreds, possibly thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This makes for a crazy cool and unique setting, but it&amp;rsquo;s also basically impossible to describe without being a god of prose or using an illustration. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to draw a world that&amp;rsquo;s just so weird and unintuitive, and I&amp;rsquo;m not good at drawing. But, I LOVE this setting, and want to do a lot more with it, but right now, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the illustrative chops to deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-characters&#34;&gt;The Characters
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dae. Our protagonist, a mechanical engineer ~20 years old working on a capstone project. That&amp;rsquo;s literally all that I developed him with. Yeah, he&amp;rsquo;s paper-thin. Following a five-man band structure, he&amp;rsquo;s nominally the Leader, but usually comes off more as the Lancer or Big Buy. When I left the story, he hadn&amp;rsquo;t really &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt; anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marc. Affable ace, best friends with Dae, who&amp;rsquo;s kinda a replacement for his often-absent parents. He switches between the Heart and the Leader. In my mind, I had him the most developed, but it&amp;rsquo;s still not great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ava. Computer programmer on the same capstone project team as Dae. I didn&amp;rsquo;t develop her much personally, but she fulfils the Smart Guy role, sometimes switching in for the Heart. Best friends with Sarah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah. Nominally the leader until she gets damseled and puppeted by Blue Sky. She has very little characterization beyond &amp;ldquo;tough guy who doesn&amp;rsquo;t take shit.&amp;rdquo; She&amp;rsquo;s basically a walking plot device, and while I planned to characterize her with a recovery from being damseled and puppeted, but stopped writing before that. I was going to do a &amp;ldquo;break the badass,&amp;rdquo; but stopped first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antonin. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t even deserve a mention, as he does basically nothing and I practically forget he exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue Sky. A moxel construction designed to maintain the Argo and protect its inhabitants, but has interpreted that directive more broadly than originally intended. It enforces a lower tech level, fights off Red Sky, and puppeteers Sarah. It&amp;rsquo;s basically amoral, only trying to fulfill the objective. Not exactly a protagonist, but was intended to be a protagonist-aligned character after they free Sarah and fight through Blue Sky&amp;rsquo;s swarms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Sky. Calls itself by a numerical address, became a paperclip maximizer focused on terraforming, as it was a bot working on the Martian terraforming effort. Intent on destroying the enclave in the Argo and using the ship&amp;rsquo;s resources to expand to the stars. The antagonist, it&amp;rsquo;s amoral, just as Blue Sky; it just has a very different objective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problems&#34;&gt;the Problems
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m just going to give a list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper-thin characters. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think them through at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uncertain story. I didn&amp;rsquo;t go in with any coherent story in mind besides a few key scenes and some twine between them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Undeveloped world. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; my world worked before writing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Undeveloped character interactions. Besides the relation between Marc and Dae, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have anything in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-fixes&#34;&gt;The Fixes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Writing a proper long-form story is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. I keep underestimating the difficulty and assuming I can plow through with gumption and goodwill. That&amp;rsquo;s not how the world works, and my poor decisions usually catch up with me around page 50. What I need to do is learn to think through a world &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;first&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Make notes, write everything down, come up with an organization system (maybe this website). Whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to organize before, I usually run into issues with quick referencing back - I can&amp;rsquo;t find the information I need. That sounds like an issue with my organization system, and I should probably try to break things down and solve the problem like an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Also, I should write short stories of the different scenes I like to get a feel for the world. The first section of the Argo story isn&amp;rsquo;t actually that bad; I basically wrote it as a short story featuring the characters I&amp;rsquo;d figured out. I think it does an alright job at characterizing them, introducing conflict, and building suspense. Those short stories are also a smaller load to try to think through. They don&amp;rsquo;t require nearly as much long-term planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The main problem I&amp;rsquo;ll run into with trying to write short stories is that I like to think &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt;. My mind will start with a short story and spiral out to the whole fictional world. This spiraling, while enticing and initially fun, tends to gloss over details and introduce inconsistencies. I need to set a specific, pre-defined endpoint to a short story and &lt;em&gt;stick to it&lt;/em&gt;. Anything more can be the subject of a future short story or part of the larger world. Who knows, maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll make its way to a post here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Max Flow</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/max-flow/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:10:57 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/max-flow/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;max-volumetric-flow&#34;&gt;Max Volumetric Flow
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; For me, this is one of the most important variables on the printer to maximize, as my motion system can support far faster movement than my nozzle. Unfortunately, I&amp;rsquo;m bad at maximizing this. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to cover all the possible issues I&amp;rsquo;ve ran into with flow rate to maybe help future printer people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;temperature&#34;&gt;Temperature
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is one of the easiest and fastest ways to increase speed - just bump up your temps. However, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a great long-term strategy. I&amp;rsquo;m skeptical of increasing temps for PLA past ~240 degrees, as that seems to be where thermal degradataion starts to become an issue and cooling is strained. It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em&gt;pointless&lt;/em&gt;, but in my experience, you start running into dimishing returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;filament-friction&#34;&gt;Filament Friction
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This wasn&amp;rsquo;t something I realized early on, but it&amp;rsquo;s obvious in hindsight - if filament is hard for your extruder to pull off the spool, your extruder won&amp;rsquo;t be able to push it to the nozzle very well. This is not great for me, as I use giant 3kg spools that have a lot of intertia. Having a bowden tube for the whole filament path seems to help a ton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;extruder-pressure&#34;&gt;Extruder Pressure
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Again, seems obvious in hindsight - if your extruder can exert more pressure, it can push more plastic out of the hotend. For me, this means just cranking down on the tensioner spring. There are practical limits from filament grinding, but this is a surprisingly good way to fix low flow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>About Me</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/about-me/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/about-me/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt; Hey there! I&amp;rsquo;m Sebastien, a young engineering student. Mostly, I love 3D printing and building stuff. I want to put stuff together and see how it all works. I also like history, biology, natural history, and just about everything. I&amp;rsquo;d usually describe myself as an affable hyper-nerd with a Wikipedia addiction, a gentle and modern ape. Give me an interesting problem, narrative, or world, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be entertained for a long while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; While I am an engineer at heart, I also like creating stories. While I am not very good at it, I&amp;rsquo;m not the worst person I&amp;rsquo;ve read. My main problem is that I can&amp;rsquo;t ever &lt;em&gt;finish&lt;/em&gt; a project, so maybe pushing some of them here will help me? I&amp;rsquo;ll see how it works out, and it&amp;rsquo;s not like anyone&amp;rsquo;s gonna kill me over some mediocre stuff I wrote on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>FLSUN SR upgrades</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/flsun-sr-upgrades/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 12:52:07 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/flsun-sr-upgrades/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flsun-super-racer&#34;&gt;The FLSUN Super Racer
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;stock-overview&#34;&gt;Stock overview
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; The SR is a delta printer created by the company FLSUN, first released a while ago. Most of its marketing is directed towards its speed, and when I bought it, the printer was a leader in off-the-shelf speed. Marketed with top speeds of 150mm/s and with stock accelerations in the 2-3k range, in the pre-bambu days, that was an impressive speed, and for only ~500 dollars, an impressive price. Sure, the printer was missing some nice features, like direct drive. Sure, it was a pretty weird configuration back when most printer used i3/cartesian systems. But I was sick of my Ender 3&amp;rsquo;s constant requirement for modification and tinkering, this thing came with a bed probe, and I had a very low budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of the stock printer:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/stock-SR.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;stock SR&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;delta-weirdness&#34;&gt;Delta weirdness
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Delta printers are weird. Cartesian and i3 motion systems make intuitive sense, but deltas take a bit more time to get used to. They&amp;rsquo;re pretty far out there compared to the other motion systems, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably just make a pros/cons list for delta printers. Overall, I love the format because it looks amazing and fits my needs very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast. Because deltas have 3 motors exerting force for every move, they can be blazingly fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable. Since the bed doesn&amp;rsquo;t move, it can be fixed in place. I don&amp;rsquo;t really need to level my bed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple. This is mostly in comparison to coreXY systems, but deltas are symmetrical and, IMO, pretty easy to get a grasp of mechanically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large print area, though with a circular bed and an emphasis on height.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time-consuming to maintain. This is more an SR thing, but replacing a nozzle is a relatively time-consuming task compared to other printers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details of the machine can get messy. Software is easy to get &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo;, but not &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;. Belt tension can be a royal pain as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low support. The system is pretty uncommon, so finding support online can be tricky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not enclosed. Not a huge issue for me, but good luck printing HIPS or ABS or anything fancier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed is &lt;em&gt;heavily&lt;/em&gt; dependent on toolhead mass. Adding direct drive will kill your speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;upgrades&#34;&gt;Upgrades
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;klipper-firmware&#34;&gt;Klipper Firmware
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; The first upgrade I tried was klipperization. I&amp;rsquo;d already klipperized my ender 3, and was somewhat familiar with the software. The SR, however, pushed me to my limits. Given the printer has basically no online documentation, this took me about a month, and I fried my board at one point. Given my difficulties, it&amp;rsquo;s probably for the best I put my experiences online somewhere to help future travelers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; First mistake: I didn&amp;rsquo;t use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/th33xitus/kiauh&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;KIAUH&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s by far the best and most useful klipperization tool, and if you aren&amp;rsquo;t using it, I recommend you start right now. It&amp;rsquo;s stupid simple, and it Just Works™.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Second mistake: I tried to follow the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cj7KpzbgExQ&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Teaching Tech video&lt;/a&gt;. The video itself is very well-made, and Teaching Tech does a great job with his explanations and walkthroughs. The problem is that there was a design change to the SR after this video was made, and now it&amp;rsquo;s entirely outdated. Modern SRs, as far as I can tell, use an MKS Robin Nano V3 board, rather than the BTT SKR V1.3. His &amp;ldquo;make menuconfig&amp;rdquo; settings are completely wrong, so here&amp;rsquo;s the settings I found worked for the nano v3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STMicroenectronics STM32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STM32F407 chip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;48 KiB bootloader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use a small, preferably 8 gig SD card formatted FAT32 with 4096 grouping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set the file name to Robin_nano_v3.bin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Third mistake: I probably fried a few boards and pins. Always be careful with wiring, always unplug when changing wiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;klipper-config&#34;&gt;Klipper Config
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m sorry my config isn&amp;rsquo;t really going to be much help, as I&amp;rsquo;ve done a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of fuckery to this printer, and the configs reflect that. I&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/Skippy33/FLSUN-SR-klipper-configs&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;post them for reference&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;DON&amp;rsquo;T&lt;/em&gt; copy-paste them. They&amp;rsquo;re for reference, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;all-metal-heatbreak&#34;&gt;All-Metal Heatbreak
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t want you to know. You &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t actually need a new hotend to have an all-metal hotend&lt;/em&gt;. You can just replace the heatbreak. I just bought a 10$ all-metal heatbreak on Amazon, anything designed for a V6 hotend will do - the specific one I bought was labeled for CR-10s. This is a super cheap upgrade that unlocks PETG and ABS printing, and all you need to do is disassemble the hotend. Overall, a 10/10 upgrade, would highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5015-fans&#34;&gt;5015 Fans
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is another pretty good no-brainer upgrade. These fans are pretty cheap on amazon, and have a &lt;em&gt;wayyy&lt;/em&gt; higher flow than the rinky-dink 4010s the SR comes with. Frankly, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why the printer comes with 4010s, as they&amp;rsquo;re woefully underpowered compared to the printer itself. However, I still found the 5015s underpowered compared to what I wanted, so I changed some more things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fan-ducts&#34;&gt;Fan Ducts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Again, the SR comes with some pretty sub-standard equipment. The ducts the printer comes with are &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt;, and running some tests, I was able to find some ducts on the internet that are a lot better. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/334581-flsun-super-racer-sr-double-fan-duct&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This one&lt;/a&gt; is the one I use, but you should probably experiment with some different models. I found all mine on printables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ducted-cooling&#34;&gt;Ducted Cooling
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This was probably my best upgrade, though it&amp;rsquo;s not for everyone. This is my DIY garage version of the common CPAP cooling upgrade. I had an old fan salvaged from a hulky Stratsys printer a school was throwing out. Initially, I used a single wide tube I&amp;rsquo;d salvaged from the same printer, and that did work for a while. However, that tube was really stiff, which was messing up my input shaper graphs. Here&amp;rsquo;s an image of the first deported fan build: &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/one-tube.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;first photo&#34;
	
	
&gt; Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s jank as hell, but it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I decided on two thin and flexible CPAP tubes. This cleaned up my input shaper graphs and actually provided more airflow. This was the best thing I ever did for my printer&amp;rsquo;s cooling, and overhangs upwards of 60% with PLA and a .6 nozzle are completely feasible and look pretty nice. If it&amp;rsquo;s an option, I&amp;rsquo;d even recommend skipping right over the 5015 fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of the fan and the eventual two tube setup:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/deported-fan.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;deported fan&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;flying-extruder&#34;&gt;Flying Extruder
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This upgrade isn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive, and is actually pretty nice, especially if you intend to enclose the printer. You see, the stock extruder sits out from the main triangle, jutting from the top. It works as a configuration, but I wanted to enclose my printer, and the easiest way to do that is to just cover the sides with big flat panels. The extruder gets in the way, and that just won&amp;rsquo;t do. So, I downloaded &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/84444-flystruder-delta-printer-flsun-sr/files&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this model&lt;/a&gt; from a lovely frenchman and printed it in PETG. The assembly was pretty easy, only taking a few M4 screws, and I just moved the stock extruder onto the plate, and presto, a flying extruder was born! I did also need to wire it up with bungee cord, but that stuff was pretty cheap. A few tips though -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The weight of the flying gantry shouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter. Ideally, the motor should be almost completely stationary as the printhead moves, &amp;ldquo;flying&amp;rdquo; above the toolhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the wires are fairly tight. If they&amp;rsquo;re too loose, the gantry will sag, messing with your input shaper graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using deported cooling, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to tie the tubes to the flying gantry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be no tension on the bowden tube. Tension on the bowden tube will destroy it in the long run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Some people, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@jamespray/videos&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;James Pray&lt;/a&gt;, will build a flying gantry without the bungee cords, instead using assemblies of springs and printed dampners. The main advantage of this setup is that the extruder can be closer to the hotend, reducing the length of the bowden tube. However, this system has a few disadvantages that make it impractical for me. This sort of system is more complex and expensive, two things I am not a fan of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I left the filament switch dangling after I removed the bar mounting it. I just push the filament through the switch and leave it hanging, but I really don&amp;rsquo;t need the switch most of the time, and I could leave a separate piece of filament in there most of the time without issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Also, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend using a reverse bowden setup between the flying extruder and the top of the printer. It&amp;rsquo;s a good way to reduce friction along the filament path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of the flying extruder:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/flying-extruder.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;flying extruder&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chc-hotend-and-cht-nozzle&#34;&gt;CHC Hotend and CHT Nozzle
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not too sure on this upgrade. They&amp;rsquo;re cheap enough through TriangleLabs on Aliexpress, and do offer some benefits over the stock hotend - it seems faster anecdotally, and they heat up &lt;em&gt;wayyyy&lt;/em&gt; faster. For 12 dollars, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend a 60-100W heater as a replacement for when your stock hotend gives out. The CHT nozzle, however, is a must-have if you want high flow rates. Anecdotally, I was noticing a ~%33 increase in volumetric flow. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the equipment to do a proper, rigorous flow test, but given that volcano CHT nozzles are nearly the same price as regular volcano nozzles through Aliexpress, it&amp;rsquo;s an upgrade I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ultralight-effector&#34;&gt;Ultralight Effector
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is maybe the first upgrade where I&amp;rsquo;ve actually questioned its necessity. I uploaded the model to printables &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/897132-flsun-sr-ultralight-effector&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it to anyone but the most diehard speedsters. I originally printed the effector in CF-PETG, and while it was much lighter than my mostly-stock effector (135g instead of 211g), it was also not stiff at all. The lack of stiffness led to terrible input shaper results despite the reduced weight. Part of that is likely my plastic, as the &amp;ldquo;carbon fiber&amp;rdquo; in the CF-PETG I was using was mostly aesthetic. Reprinting in PLA led to input shaper near-equivalent to the stock effector. In dicussion with some delta printer gurus such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@jamespray/videos&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;cophaeler&lt;/a&gt;, I was pointed to another issue that could be leading to my input shaper spikes - frame stiffness. I&amp;rsquo;ve attatched my input shaper graphs, and even with quite different configurations, the peak at 50hz is very consistent. This points to frame (or possibly table) stiffness as a greater contributor to vibrations in my case. I&amp;rsquo;ll do some more experimenting and investigating, especually the possibiltiy that I need to tighten some screws or check my flying extruder setup. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;ll say this upgrade has dubious value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PETG graph -
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ultralight_PETG_shaper_calibrate_x.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;flying extruder&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLA graph -
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ultralight_PLA_shaper_calibrate_x.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;flying extruder&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; So, what did I get out of all of this? At the start, stock speeds were ~150mm/s at 3k mm/s^2. The deported cooling and klipperization got recommended accelerations to ~6k and top speeds of ~250mm/s. Making the tubes more flexible, and those accelerations are pushed to ~10k. I haven&amp;rsquo;t ran any speedbenchies, but print times are between 1/2 and 1/3 stock times, depending on the print. Overall, for the price, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad. And to be honest, I really liked the process of modifying and building up the printer to its current capabilities. However, my biggest cap hasn&amp;rsquo;t really changed - flow rate. I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure out how to increase flow rate without decreasing my bank account or increasing temperatures past reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>FLSUN SR upgrades logs &#43; notes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/flsun-sr-upgrades-logs--notes/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 12:52:07 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/flsun-sr-upgrades-logs--notes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flsun-super-racer&#34;&gt;The FLSUN Super Racer
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;stock-overview&#34;&gt;Stock overview
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; The Super Racer(!) is a delta printer created by the company FLSUN, first released a while ago. Most of its marketing is directed towards its speed, and when I bought it, the printer was a leader in off-the-shelf speed. Marketed with top speeds of 150mm/s and with stock accelerations in the 2-3k range, in the pre-bambu days, that was an impressive speed, and for only ~500 dollars, an impressive price. Sure, the printer was missing some nice features, like direct drive. Sure, it was a pretty weird configuration back when most printer used i3/cartesian systems. But I was sick of my Ender 3&amp;rsquo;s constant requirement for modification and tinkering, this thing came with a bed probe, and I had a very low budget. So, I picked one up on a trip to Microcenter, named it Joshua, and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of the stock printer:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/stock-SR.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;stock SR&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;delta-weirdness&#34;&gt;Delta weirdness
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Delta printers are weird. Cartesian and i3 motion systems make intuitive sense, but deltas take a bit more time to get used to. They&amp;rsquo;re pretty far out there compared to the other motion systems, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably just make a pros/cons list for delta printers. Overall, I love the format because it looks amazing and fits my needs very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast. Because deltas have 3 motors exerting force for every move, they can be blazingly fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable. Since the bed doesn&amp;rsquo;t move, it can be fixed in place. I don&amp;rsquo;t really need to level my bed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple. This is mostly in comparison to coreXY systems, but deltas are symmetrical and, IMO, pretty easy to get a grasp of mechanically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large print area, though with a circular bed and an emphasis on height.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time-consuming to maintain. This is more an SR thing, but replacing a nozzle is a relatively time-consuming task compared to other printers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Details of the machine can get messy. Software is easy to get &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo;, but not &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;. Belt tension can be a royal pain as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low support. The system is pretty uncommon, so finding support online can be tricky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not enclosed. Not a huge issue for me, but good luck printing HIPS or ABS or anything fancier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed is &lt;em&gt;heavily&lt;/em&gt; dependent on toolhead mass. Adding direct drive will kill your speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;upgrades&#34;&gt;Upgrades
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;klipper-firmware&#34;&gt;Klipper Firmware
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; The first upgrade I tried was klipperization. I&amp;rsquo;d already klipperized my ender 3, and was somewhat familiar with the software. The SR, however, pushed me to my limits. Given the printer has basically no online documentation, this took me about a month, and I fried my board at one point. Given my difficulties, it&amp;rsquo;s probably for the best I put my experiences online somewhere to help future travelers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; First mistake: I didn&amp;rsquo;t use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/th33xitus/kiauh&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;KIAUH&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s by far the best and most useful klipperization tool, and if you aren&amp;rsquo;t using it, I recommend you start right now. It&amp;rsquo;s stupid simple, and it Just Works™.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Second mistake: I tried to follow the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cj7KpzbgExQ&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Teaching Tech video&lt;/a&gt;. The video itself is very well-made, and Teaching Tech does a great job with his explanations and walkthroughs. The problem is that there was a design change to the SR after this video was made, and now it&amp;rsquo;s entirely outdated. Modern SRs, as far as I can tell, use an MKS Robin Nano V3 board, rather than the BTT SKR V1.3. His &amp;ldquo;make menuconfig&amp;rdquo; settings are completely wrong, so here&amp;rsquo;s the settings I found worked for the nano v3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STMicroenectronics STM32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STM32F407 chip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;48 KiB bootloader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use a small, preferably 8 gig SD card formatted FAT32 with 4096 grouping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set the file name to Robin_nano_v3.bin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Third mistake: I probably fried a few boards and pins. Always be careful with wiring, always unplug when changing wiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;klipper-config&#34;&gt;Klipper Config
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m sorry my config isn&amp;rsquo;t really going to be much help, as I&amp;rsquo;ve done a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of fuckery to this printer, and the configs reflect that. I&amp;rsquo;ll &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/Skippy33/FLSUN-SR-klipper-configs&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;post them for reference&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;DON&amp;rsquo;T&lt;/em&gt; copy-paste them. They&amp;rsquo;re for reference, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;all-metal-heatbreak&#34;&gt;All-Metal Heatbreak
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip &lt;strong&gt;they&lt;/strong&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t want you to know. You &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t actually need a new hotend to have an all-metal hotend&lt;/em&gt;. You can just replace the heatbreak. I just bought a 10$ all-metal heatbreak on Amazon, anything designed for a V6 hotend will do - the specific one I bought was labeled for CR-10s. This is a super cheap upgrade that unlocks PETG and ABS printing, and all you need to do is disassemble the hotend. Overall, a 10/10 upgrade, would highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5015-fans&#34;&gt;5015 Fans
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is another pretty good no-brainer upgrade. These fans are pretty cheap on amazon, and have a &lt;em&gt;wayyy&lt;/em&gt; higher flow than the rinky-dink 4010s the SR comes with. Frankly, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why the printer comes with 4010s, as they&amp;rsquo;re woefully underpowered compared to the printer itself. However, I still found the 5015s underpowered compared to what I wanted, so I changed some more things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fan-ducts&#34;&gt;Fan Ducts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; Again, the SR comes with some pretty sub-standard equipment. The ducts the printer comes with are &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt;, and running some tests, I was able to find some ducts on the internet that are a lot better. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/334581-flsun-super-racer-sr-double-fan-duct&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This one&lt;/a&gt; is the one I use, but you should probably experiment with some different models. I found all mine on printables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ducted-cooling&#34;&gt;Ducted Cooling
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This was probably my best upgrade, though it&amp;rsquo;s not for everyone. This is my DIY garage version of the common CPAP cooling upgrade. I had an old fan salvaged from a hulky Stratsys printer a school was throwing out. Initially, I used a single wide tube I&amp;rsquo;d salvaged from the same printer, and that did work for a while. However, that tube was really stiff, which was messing up my input shaper graphs. Here&amp;rsquo;s an image of the first deported fan build: &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/one-tube.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;first photo&#34;
	
	
&gt; Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s jank as hell, but it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I decided on two thin and flexible CPAP tubes. This cleaned up my input shaper graphs and actually provided more airflow. This was the best thing I ever did for my printer&amp;rsquo;s cooling, and overhangs upwards of 60% with PLA and a .6 nozzle are completely feasible and look pretty nice. If it&amp;rsquo;s an option, I&amp;rsquo;d even recommend skipping right over the 5015 fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of the fan and the eventual two tube setup:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/deported-fan.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;deported fan&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;flying-extruder&#34;&gt;Flying Extruder
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This upgrade isn&amp;rsquo;t too expensive, and is actually pretty nice, especially if you intend to enclose the printer. You see, the stock extruder sits out from the main triangle, jutting from the top. It works as a configuration, but I wanted to enclose my printer, and the easiest way to do that is to just cover the sides with big flat panels. The extruder gets in the way, and that just won&amp;rsquo;t do. So, I downloaded &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/84444-flystruder-delta-printer-flsun-sr/files&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this model&lt;/a&gt; from a lovely frenchman and printed it in PETG. The assembly was pretty easy, only taking a few M4 screws, and I just moved the stock extruder onto the plate, and presto, a flying extruder was born! I did also need to wire it up with bungee cord, but that stuff was pretty cheap. A few tips though -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The weight of the flying gantry shouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter. Ideally, the motor should be almost completely stationary as the printhead moves, &amp;ldquo;flying&amp;rdquo; above the toolhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the wires are fairly tight. If they&amp;rsquo;re too loose, the gantry will sag, messing with your input shaper graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using deported cooling, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to tie the tubes to the flying gantry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be no tension on the bowden tube. Tension on the bowden tube will destroy it in the long run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Some people, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@jamespray/videos&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;James Pray&lt;/a&gt;, will build a flying gantry without the bungee cords, instead using assemblies of springs and printed dampners. The main advantage of this setup is that the extruder can be closer to the hotend, reducing the length of the bowden tube. However, this system has a few disadvantages that make it impractical for me. This sort of system is more complex and expensive, two things I am not a fan of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I left the filament switch dangling after I removed the bar mounting it. I just push the filament through the switch and leave it hanging, but I really don&amp;rsquo;t need the switch most of the time, and I could leave a separate piece of filament in there most of the time without issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Also, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend using a reverse bowden setup between the flying extruder and the top of the printer. It&amp;rsquo;s a good way to reduce friction along the filament path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of the flying extruder:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/flying-extruder.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;flying extruder&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chc-hotend-and-cht-nozzle&#34;&gt;CHC Hotend and CHT Nozzle
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not too sure on this upgrade. They&amp;rsquo;re cheap enough through TriangleLabs on Aliexpress, and do offer some benefits over the stock hotend - it seems faster anecdotally, and they heat up &lt;em&gt;wayyyy&lt;/em&gt; faster. For 12 dollars, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend a 60-100W heater as a replacement for when your stock hotend gives out. The CHT nozzle, however, is a must-have if you want high flow rates. Anecdotally, I was noticing a ~%33 increase in volumetric flow. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the equipment to do a proper, rigorous flow test, but given that volcano CHT nozzles are nearly the same price as regular volcano nozzles through Aliexpress, it&amp;rsquo;s an upgrade I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ultralight-effector&#34;&gt;Ultralight Effector
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is maybe the first upgrade where I&amp;rsquo;ve actually questioned its necessity. I uploaded the model to printables &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/897132-flsun-sr-ultralight-effector&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it to anyone but the most diehard speedsters. I originally printed the effector in CF-PETG, and while it was much lighter than my mostly-stock effector (135g instead of 211g), it was also not stiff at all. The lack of stiffness led to terrible input shaper results despite the reduced weight. Part of that is likely my plastic, as the &amp;ldquo;carbon fiber&amp;rdquo; in the CF-PETG I was using was mostly aesthetic. Reprinting in PLA led to input shaper near-equivalent to the stock effector. In dicussion with some delta printer gurus such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@jamespray/videos&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;cophaeler&lt;/a&gt;, I was pointed to another issue that could be leading to my input shaper spikes - frame stiffness. I&amp;rsquo;ve attatched my input shaper graphs, and even with quite different configurations, the peak at 50hz is very consistent. This points to frame (or possibly table) stiffness as a greater contributor to vibrations in my case. I&amp;rsquo;ll do some more experimenting and investigating, especually the possibiltiy that I need to tighten some screws or check my flying extruder setup. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;ll say this upgrade has dubious value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PETG graph -
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ultralight_PETG_shaper_calibrate_x.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;flying extruder&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLA graph -
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/ultralight_PLA_shaper_calibrate_x.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;flying extruder&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; So, what did I get out of all of this? At the start, stock speeds were ~150mm/s at 3k mm/s^2. The deported cooling and klipperization got recommended accelerations to ~6k and top speeds of ~250mm/s. Making the tubes more flexible, and those accelerations are pushed to ~10k. I haven&amp;rsquo;t ran any speedbenchies, but print times are between 1/2 and 1/3 stock times, depending on the print. Overall, for the price, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad. And to be honest, I really liked the process of modifying and building up the printer to its current capabilities. However, my biggest cap hasn&amp;rsquo;t really changed - flow rate. I can&amp;rsquo;t really figure out how to increase flow rate without decreasing my bank account or increasing temperatures past reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Reference</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/reference/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 21:04:56 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/reference/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;h1-block&#34;&gt;H1 Block
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;h2-block&#34;&gt;H2 Block
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-so-on&#34;&gt;and so on
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a reference that should only ever be visible in draft mode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, and this is &lt;em&gt;italicized&lt;/em&gt; text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a blockquote&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is an ordered list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;item1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;item2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;item3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is an unordered list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;itema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;itemb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;itemc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;print(&amp;quot;HellO! This is a code block!&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s something that needs a footnote &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s something that needs a definition&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;definition&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;and here&amp;rsquo;s something stupid&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and here&amp;rsquo;s an emoji :joy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s something that needs ==highlighting==.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And my chem teacher will shoot me if I don&amp;rsquo;t properly ~subscript~ and ^superscript^.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/cheat-sheet/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This is the markdown cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is an image
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/puppies.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;puppies!&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and here&amp;rsquo;s the footnote&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
